Filip Nikšić

Department of Computer and Information Science Phone: +1 215 454-9531

University of Pennsylvania

Email: fniksic@seas.upenn.edu 3330 Walnut St, Philadelphia, PA 19104, USA Web: https://fniksic.github.io

Research Interests Broadly, I am interested in the analysis, verification, and testing of concurrent

> and distributed systems. My doctoral research focused on applying combinatorial techniques to systematic and random testing of distributed systems. More recently, I have been working on programming models and testing techniques

for distributed stream processing.

Education

09/2012-05/2019 Max Planck Institute for Software Systems (MPI-SWS)

Doctor of Engineering (Dr.-Ing.) degree by Technische Universität Kaiserslautern

Dissertation: Combinatorial Constructions for Effective Testing

Grade: summa cum laude

10/2009-10/2011 Department of Mathematics, University of Zagreb

Enrolled in a doctoral program in mathematics

Department of Mathematics, University of Zagreb 07/2004-10/2009

Dipl. Ing. (4-year degree) in Mathematics (profile: Computer Science)

GPA: 4.7 / 5.0

Work Experience

10/2018-present University of Pennsylvania

Postdoctoral researcher, working with Rajeev Alur

09/2012-10/2018 Max Planck Institute for Software Systems (MPI-SWS)

Doctoral researcher, advised by Rupak Majumdar

Microsoft Corp., Redmond, Washington 05/2016-08/2016

Research intern working on a testing and fault-injection framework for concurrent

software. Technologies: C#, .NET Compiler Platform ("Roslyn")

04/2010-09/2012 IN2 d.o.o., Zagreb, Croatia

Software engineer developing financial software. Technologies: Oracle DB (SQL,

PL/SQL), Java (Spring Framework), and Adobe Flex

Teaching Experience

01/2019-05/2019 University of Pennsylvania

Occasional lectures and a student project for CIS 540: Principles of Embedded

Computation (Spring 2019)

10/2016-02/2017 Max Planck Institute for Software Systems (MPI-SWS)

Teaching assistant: Program Analysis (Winter 2016/2017)

04/2014-07/2014 Max Planck Institute for Software Systems (MPI-SWS)

Teaching assistant: Verification of Reactive Systems (Summer 2014)

03/2008-09/2009 Department of Mathematics, University of Zagreb

Student assistant: Set Theory (Summer 2008), Introduction to Parallel Comput-

ing (Winter 2008), Application of Parallel Computers (Summer 2009).

09/2002-06/2005 Informatics Club NET, Ivanić-Grad

Tutored high school students for programming competitions

Professional Service Artifact evaluation committee: ISSTA 2015, ECOOP 2018, CAV 2019

Conference reviews: CAV 2013, CSL 2013, FMCAD 2013, EMSOFT 2014, FMCAD 2014, LICS 2014, CADE 2015, VMCAI 2015, POPL 2016, TACAS 2016, VMCAI

2017, ICALP 2018

Journal reviews: ACM Transactions on Computational Logic, Acta Informatica

Technical Skills

Operating systems: GNU/Linux, Mac OS X, Windows

Programming languages: C/C++, C#, Java, Python, PL/SQL, ActionScript (Flex)

Databases: Oracle DB

Language Skills Croatian (native), English (fluent), German (basic)

Publications Burcu Kulahcioglu Ozkan, Rupak Majumdar, F. N. Checking Linearizability Using

Hitting Families. PPoPP 2019

Burcu Kulahcioglu Ozkan, Rupak Majumdar, F. N., Mitra Tabaei Befrouei, Georg Weissenbacher. Randomized Testing of Distributed Systems with Probabilistic

Guarantees. PACMPL 2 (OOPSLA) 2018

Rupak Majumdar, F. N. Why is Random Testing Effective for Partition Tolerance

Bugs? PACMPL 2 (POPL) 2018

Dmitry Chistikov, Rupak Majumdar, F. N. Hitting Families of Schedules for Asyn-

chronous Programs. CAV 2016

Ivan Gavran, F. N., Aditya Kanade, Rupak Majumdar, Viktor Vafeiadis. Rely/Gua-

rantee Reasoning for Asynchronous Programs. CONCUR 2015

Sumit Gulwani, Mikaël Mayer, F. N., Ruzica Piskac. StriSynth: Synthesis for Live

Programming. ICSE 2015

Javier Esparza, Ruslán Ledesma-Garza, Rupak Majumdar, Philipp Meyer, F. N. An

SMT-Based Approach to Coverability Analysis. CAV 2014

Johannes Kloos, Rupak Majumdar, F. N., Ruzica Piskac. Incremental, Inductive

Coverability. CAV 2013

Philadelphia, March 4, 2020